Guide to the Robert Ward Papers, 1910-2012 and undated RL.01344
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Operas, 1956-2012 and undated; 3
  - Roman Fever, 1987-2002 and undated; 9
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0037)
    - JE-001, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0038)
      PBS version copy
    - RF-010, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0039)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0040)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0041)
    - Reel 1, undated (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0058)
    - Reel 2, undated (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0059)
    - Academic writings on Roman Fever, "Operas from the American Music Theater Project", undated (Box 56)
    - Shooting script, television production, undated (Box 56)
    - Published libretto and drafts, 1987-1993; 4 folders (Box 56)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 56)
    - Orchestral score, 1993 (Box 56)
    - Orchestral score master sheets, undated; 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Piano-vocal scores with markings, 1993 and undated; 4 folders (Box 56)
    - Original uncorrected manuscript, undated (Box 57)
  - Debs, 2007-2008; 10
    - Libretto drafts, 2007-2008 (Box 63)
- Instrumental Works, 1942-2010 and undated; 4
  Instrumental Works is comprised of Robert Ward's compositions for orchestra, wind ensemble, concert band, and a variety of chamber ensembles. Most of the pieces include newspaper clippings, programs, and reviews from performances, including premieres. Almost all pieces include music sketches, piano reductions, full scores, orchestral scores, conductor's scores, and complete sets of parts. Many pieces also have recordings, when noted. Media types include audiocassettes, compact discs, digital audio tapes, DVDs, and VHS tapes. The scores include published versions, edited proofs—many in Ward's own hand—master sheets, printing masters, and original manuscripts. Recording titles are taken from the media objects themselves. Arranged alphabetically by title of piece.
  - Adagio and Allegro, 1945-1972 and undated; 11
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 0, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0002)
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, letter, 1945-1972 (Box 9)
    - Orchestral score, 1953 (Box 63)
    - Orchestral score with some markings, undated; 11.5" x 14" (Box 68)
  - Adventures in Sharps and Flats, undated; 12
    - Original manuscript, undated (Box 68)
  - Andante and Scherzo for Strings, undated; 13
    - Orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 68)
  - Antiphony for Winds, 1965-1985 and undated; 14
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, correspondence, 1965-1985 (Box 9)
    - University of Tennessee Orchestra and Wind Ensemble, 16 May 1981 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0206)
    - Keystone Winds, conducted by Jack Stamp, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0218)
    - Brevard Music Center Symphonic Band, 28 Junl 1986 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0219)
    - TAC Concert Band, May 1991 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0220)
    - Harding University Wind Ensemble, 2008 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0005)
    - The Keystone Wind Ensemble, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0068)
    - Night Fantasy: Music for Winds, by the Keystone Wind Ensemble, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0086)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0006)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0044)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0043)
    - Full score and two complete sets of parts, 1973 (Box 63)
      One set is missing Horn IV part
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 68)
  - Appalachian Ditties and Dances, 1988-2007 and undated; 15
    - Newspaper clipping, programs, reviews, letter, 1988-2007 (Box 9)
    - Robert Ward works for violin and piano, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0094)
      Vartan Manoogian and Anne Epperson
    - Amadeus Trio, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0176)
    - Amy Mugavero, violin, and Michael Ching, piano, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0212)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0044)
    - Echoes in America: Chamber Music of Robert Ward, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0069)
    - Unknown performers, 1990 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0087)
    - Premiere, Music in the Mountains, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0005)
    - Music sketches, master sheets, full score with cello and violin versions, 1991 and undated (Box 63)
  - An Appalachian Story, 1991; 16
    - Full score, 1991 (Box 63)
  - Aria, undated; 17
    - Orchestral score and string parts master sheets, undated; 2 folders (Box 64)
    - Orchestral score and flute part with markings, undated; 11.5" x 14.5" (Box 68)
  - Arioso and Tarantelle, 1955-2008; 18
    - Newspaper clipping, programs, 1955-2008 (Box 9)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0033)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0032)
      Liner notes list Duke faculty performers
    - Music for Our Times, WCPE, 3 October 1987 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0050)
    - Arioso for Cello and Piano, unknown performers, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0095)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0168)
    - For viola and piano, unknown performers, 2008 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0014)
    - For cello and piano, unknown performers, 1996 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0016)
    - Tarantelle for cello and piano, Robert Ward Chamber Music, 1979 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0009)
    - Tarantelle for cello and piano, unknown performers, undated (Box 32, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0056)
    - Arioso for cello and piano, unknown performers, undated (Box 32, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0057)
    - Complete score and parts for viola and cello versions, 1960 (Box 64)
  - Assorted short solo piano works, 1953 and undated; 19
    - Score for Two Pieces for the Piano; includes "Dancing," "Slumber Song," and "Song", 1953 and undated (Box 64)
    - Two Pieces for the Piano, score, undated; 11.5" x 14.5" (Box 68)
  - Bayou Rhapsody, 2001-2002 and undated; 20
    - Program, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Rehearsal tape, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0217)
    - Collage Pastiche, 28 May 2002 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0090)
    - Orginal manuscript and sketches, undated (Box 64)
    - Full score and complete parts, 2001 (Box 64)
  - The Beginnings, 2007; 21
    - Program, 2007 (Box 9)
    - Ward Recording 44.1K #1, take 6, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0016)
    - Ward Recording 48K #1, take 6, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0018)
    - North Carolina Symphony, conducted by Grant Llewellyn, 5 May 2007 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0028)
    - Orchestral score, 2007 (Box 64)
    - Orchestral scores with some markings and program notes, 2007; 11" x 14.5" (Box 68)
  - Brass Ablaze, 1996 and undated; 22
    - Program, poster, 1996 (Box 9)
    - Triangle Brass Band, conducted by Michael Votta, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0160)
    - Full scores, 1996; 2 folders (Box 64)
    - Music sketches and original manuscript, undated (Box 68)
  - By the Way of Memories, 1990-1997 and undated; 23
    - Programs, 1992-1997 (Box 9)
    - Conducted by Pavel Prantl, takes 73-103, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0003)
    - Conducted by Pavel Prantl, takes 104-170, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0004)
    - Prague Chamber Orchestra, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0103)
    - Performance Today, 17 April 1991 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0164)
    - National Gallery Concert, Washington D.C., 5 April 1992 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0174)
    - National Gallery Orchestra, conducted by George Manos, 6 April 1997 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0175)
    - National Gallery Orchestra, conducted by George Manos, 6 April 1997 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0214)
    - World premiere, 1999 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0088)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 64)
    - Original manuscript, undated (Box 64)
    - Orchestral scores, 1990-1991; 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Celebrations of God in Nature, 1980-2002 and undated; 24
    - Programs, 1980-2002 (Box 9)
    - Clarence Cloak, organist, 7 June 1992 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0167)
    - Westminster Presbyterian, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, 7 June 1987 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0010)
    - Music sketches, original manuscript, full score with markings, 1980 and undated (Box 64)
  - City of Oaks, 2008; 25
    - Program, 2008 (Box 9)
    - Orchestral score, 2008 (Box 64)
  - Concert Music for Orchestra, 1948 and undated; 26
    - Newspaper clipping, program, 1948 (Box 9)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 64)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 68)
    - Orchestral score, undated; 11.5" x 15" (Box 68)
  - Concertino for Strings, 1973-1998; 27
    - Newspaper, programs, 1973-1998 (Box 9)
    - North Carolina: Its Music and its Composers; St. Stephens Chamber Orchestra, 1 March 1992 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0015)
    - Central Minnesota Chamber Orchestra, conducted by Ching-Hsin Hsu, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0163)
    - St. Stephens Chamber Orchestra, conducted by Lorenzo Muti, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0165)
    - St. Stephens Chamber Orchestra, conducted by Lorenzo Muti, 1 March 1992 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0179)
    - American String Congress, Western Division, conducted by James Van Horn, 29 June 1978 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0180)
    - The North Carolinians, St. Stephen's Chamber Orchestra, conducted by Lorenzo Muti, 1993 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0065)
    - Conductors Guild, South Carolina, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0008)
    - Orchestral scores with markings, 1993 (Box 64)
  - Concerto for Piano and Orchestra, 1968-2009 and undated; 28
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, photograph, program notes, 1968-2009 (Box 9)
    - Stuttgart Radio Orchestra, 1989 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0011)
    - North Carolina Symphony, conducted by Grant Llewellyn with Jamaes Dick, piano, 4 May 2007 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0028)
    - Stuttgart Radio Orchestra, 1999 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0088)
    - Stuttgart Radio Orchestra, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0003)
    - National Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Howard Mitchell and with Marjorie Mitchell, piano, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0030)
    - Two-piano and orchestral scores, 1970; 3 folders (Box 64)
    - Two-piano score, undated; 10" x 13" (Box 69)
    - Conductor's scores with markings, undated; 2 folders (Box 69)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 70)
  - Concerto for Saxophone and Orchestra, 1983-2003 and undated; 29
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1983-2003 (Box 10)
    - North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Gerhardt Zimmerman, James Houlik on saxophone, 1988 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0025)
    - Robert Ward Celebration, final edit, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0032)
    - North Carolina Symphony, version two, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0044)
    - North Carolina Symphony, 8 October 1987 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0067)
    - World Premiere, Charlotte Symphony Orchestra, 15 February 1984 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0187)
    - United States Air Force Orchestra, conducted by Robert Ward and with James Houlik on saxophone, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0188)
    - Arrangement for Concert Band, Duke Wind Symphony with James Houlik on saxophone, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0190)
    - Keystone Winds, conducted by Jack Stamp, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0218)
    - North Carolina Symphony, conducted by Gerhardt Zimmermann with James Houlik on saxophone, 1996 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0008)
    - Concernt band arrangement, the Keystone Wind Ensemble, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0068)
    - Night Fantasy: Music for Winds, arrangement for concert band, Keystone Wind Ensemble, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0086)
    - North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, 1988 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0017)
    - Test pressing, North Carolina Symphony Orchestra, 1988 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0021)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 64)
    - Manuscript photocopy of saxophone part, undated (Box 64)
    - Piano scores, includes first version and revised version, 1989 and undated; 4 folders (Box 64)
      Includes saxophone part and Robert Ward's copy with markings
    - Orchestral score, Movement II, undated (Box 64)
    - Concert band arrangement, 1993 (Box 64)
      Includes program notes
    - Orchestral score master sheets and proofs, undated (Box 70)
    - Conductor's scores with markings, undated (Box 70)
  - Concerto for Violin and Orchestra, 1991-1998 and undated; 30
    - Commission of Concerto for Violin and Orchestra, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
      Correspondence, program, contracts
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1991-1998 (Box 10)
    - Winston-Salem Symphony, 11 January 1994 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0001)
    - Robert Ward Interview and world premiere of Concerto for Violin and Orchestra on NPR's "Performance Today", 3 February 1994 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0033)
    - Dekalb Symphony Orchestra, Dekalb College Central Campus, 7 October 1997 (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0070)
    - Winston-Salem Piedmont Triad Orchestra, conducted by Peter Perret, Sarah Johnson on Violin, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0117)
    - Dubbed from master CD, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0119)
    - Winston-Salem Piedmont Triad Orchestra, conducted by Peter Perret and with Sarah Johnson, violin, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0189)
    - Bakersfield Symphony with Sarah Johnson, violin, 17 April 1994 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0195)
    - World Premiere, Winston-Salem Piedmont Tirad Symphony, conducted by Peter Perret, 9 Januart 1994 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0196)
    - Winston-Salem Triad Piedmont Symphony, conducted by Peter Perret, 1994 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0070)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 64)
    - Original masters of orchestral score and violin part, undated; 2 folders (Box 64)
    - Piano score and violin part, 1993 (Box 64)
    - Orchestral scores, 1993; 2 folders (Box 65)
      Includes Robert Ward's copies with final revisions
    - Orchestral score original manuscript and master sheets, undated; 2 folders (Box 70)
  - Dialogue on the Tides of Time, 1987 and undated; 31
    - Newspaper clipping, programs, 1987 (Box 10)
    - Carolina Memorial Concert for Peace, Duke Chapel, 26 May 1987 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0045)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 65)
    - Piano score and complete parts, undated (Box 65)
  - Dialogues: A Triple Concerto for Violin, Cello, Piano with Orchestra, 1982-2009 and undated; 32
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1982-2009 (Box 10)
    - Conducted by Pavel Prantl, takes 44-72, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0002)
    - Ward Recording 44.1K #1, take 6, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0016)
    - Ward Recording 44.1K #2, take 7, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0017)
    - Ward Recording 48K #1, take 6, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0018)
    - Ward Recording 48K #2, take 7, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0019)
    - Dub from master cassette, Florida, February 1985 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0003)
    - The Chamber Orchestra of the Triangle, 9 March 2003 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0005)
    - Prague Chamber Orchestra, undated (Box 17, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0103)
    - Chattanooga Symphony, conducted by Richard Cromier, 5 April 1983 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0178)
    - Triangle Chamber Orchestra, 2007 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0006)
    - American Romanian Festival, 5 November 2009 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0022)
    - Arman Trio and W. Piedmont Symphony, 18 October 2003 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0030)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0083)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 65)
    - Orchestral score, 1986 (Box 65)
    - Piano score and soloist parts, 1986 (Box 65)
    - Orchestral and piano scores, revised version, 2002 (Box 65)
    - Piano score and soloist parts manuscript photocopy with markings, undated (Box 65)
    - Conductor's scores, undated (Box 71)
    - Piano scores, undated; 11" x 14" (Box 71)
    - Origjnal manuscript, music sketches, program notes, undated (Box 71)
  - Dialogues for Violin, Cello, and Piano, 1984-2003 and undated; 33
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1984-2003 (Box 10)
    - Recorded by WUNC at Duke University East campus, 4 February 1984 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0004)
    - Amadeus Trio, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0006)
    - University of Wisconsin students and faculty, September 1991 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0064)
    - Manuel Capote on cello, Michael Ching on piano, Amy Mugavero on violin, undated (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0169)
    - Amadeus Trio, undated (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0176)
    - Re-edits with ID number for movements, 17 December 2006 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0020)
    - Edited copy, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0023)
    - Armon Trio, 6 October 2002 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0043)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0044)
    - Robert Ward compilation CD, evaluation CD #2, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0058)
    - Echoes in America: Chamber Music of Robert Ward, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0069)
    - St. Stephen's Chamber Orchestra, conducted by Lorenzo Muti, 1990 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0087)
    - Full score and parts, chamber version, undated (Box 65)
    - Master sheets xerox and original mock-ups, undated (Box 65)
    - First revision of piano part, undated (Box 65)
  - Divertimento for Orchestra, 1966-2003 and undated; 34
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1967-2003 (Box 10)
    - Portland Youth Philharmonic, conducted by Jacob Avshalomov, 1994 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0007)
    - Portland Junior Symphony, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0016)
    - Contemporary Youth Orchestra, 23 March 2003 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0037)
    - Orchestral scores, 1966 (Box 65)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 71)
    - Orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 71)
    - Conductor's score, undated (Box 72)
  - Echoes of America, 1997-2001 and undated; 35
    - Newspaper clipping, programs, 1997-2001 (Box 10)
    - Aurora Musicalis, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0045)
    - Echoes in America: Chamber Music of Robert Ward, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0069)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 65)
    - Full score and parts, 1997; 2 folders (Box 65)
      Includes Robert Ward's copy and edited parts
  - Euphony for Orchestra, 1957-2005 and undated; 36
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, 1961-2005 (Box 10)
    - Louiseville Records, Bay Cities mono, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0025)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0042)
    - Southwest Michigan Symphony Orchestra, 13 January 1990 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0061)
    - American Masters Concert II: The Music of Robert Ward, 10 March 2002 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0040)
    - Louisville Orchestra, 1989 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0066)
    - Louisville Orchestra, conducted by Robert Whitney, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0020)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0044)
    - Louisville Orchestra, conducted by Robert Whitney, stereo, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0028)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0043)
    - Music sketches, manuscript copy, orchestral score master sheets, undated (Box 72)
    - Orchestral score, 1957 (Box 65)
  - Fatal Interview, undated; 37
    - Conductor's score, orchestral score master sheets, original manuscript, undated (Box 72)
  - Fanfare for Durham, 1987-1988 and undated; 38
    - Newspaper, program, 1988 (Box 10)
    - ECS Publishing Wind Ensemble sampler, 1996 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0048)
    - Keystone Winds, conducted by Jack Stamp, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0218)
    - The Keystone Wind Ensemble, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0068)
    - Night Fantasy: Music for Winds, by the Keystone Wind Ensemble, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0086)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 65)
    - Full score, complete parts, and original version master proofs, 1987 (Box 65)
  - Fantasia for Brass and Timpani, 1957-1991 and undated; 39
    - Programs, letter, 1968-1991 (Box 10)
    - American Festival for the Arts, 15 June 1996 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0031)
    - TAC Band, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, 9 November 1991, 11 November 1991 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0063)
    - University of Wisconsin students and faculty, September 1990 (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0064)
    - University of Delaware Brass, Dan Pressler and wife, undated (Box 16, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0066)
    - Keystone Winds, conducted by Jack Stamp, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0218)
    - The Keystone Wind Ensemble, 1998 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0068)
    - Night Fantasy: Music for Winds, by the Keystone Wind Ensemble, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0086)
    - Julliard School of Music, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0005)
    - Polish Radio Orchestra, conducted by Bodhan Wodiczko and Zdzislav Szostak, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0018)
    - Polish Radio Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Zdzislaw Szestak, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0009)
    - Full score and complete parts, 1957 (Box 65)
    - Music sketches and full score master sheets, undated (Box 72)
  - Festive Ode, 1966-1995 and undated; 40
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, reviews, correspondence, 1966-1995 (Box 10)
    - The Polish National Radio Orchestra, conducted by William Strickland, 2000 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0004)
    - Louisville Orchestra, 1989 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0066)
    - Polish Radio Orchestra, conducted by Bodhan Wodiczko and Zdzislav Szostak, undated (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0018)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0044)
    - Sch. 17th Annual Forum; Milwakee Symphony, mono, 3 October 1966 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0033)
    - Depauw University Contemporary Music Festival, Festival Guest Composer/Conductor Robert Ward, 16 April 1980 (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0043)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 72)
    - Orchestral score with markings, 1976 (Box 65)
    - Conductor's score, undated (Box 72)
  - Festival Triptych, 1986 and undated; 41
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, program notes, 1986 (Box 10)
    - Eastern Music Festival Orchestra, conducted by Shelly Morgenstern, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0129)
    - Eastern Music Festival Orchestra, conducted by Shelly Morgenstern, undated (Box 18, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0130)
    - Unknown performers, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0004)
    - Music sketches, undated (Box 65)
    - Original unrevised orchestral score with markings, undated; 2 folders (Box 65)
  - Fiesta Processional, 1967-1977 and undated; 42
    - Newspaper clippings, programs, 1967-1977 (Box 10)